<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Interior of a Cobra Mk III</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
      <p>The Cobra is essentially a single-pilot trade-ship, but has
      been designed to support a second person, provided
      that person is of ordinary human or humanoid dimensions
      and physiology. The ship itself consists of five main areas:</p>
      <p>[bp]The cargo hold[/pb] fills the bulk of the mid-space area, and
      the cargo bay doors open downwards. The capacity in an
      unmodified Cobra is 20 1-tonne canisters. Extra cargo
      space may be acquired by extending the cargo bay,
      which does not affect manoeuvrability. Tonne canisters
      (TC) attach magnetically to the cargo arms within the
      bay, and two AutoShuttles occupy the central space.</p>
      <p>[bp]The bridge[/pb] has seats for pilot and co-pilot, a MedStim
      Centre, entrance to the escape pod, descent well to living
      quarters, communications console, special suit locker,
      RemLock supply case, attachment facilities for AutoDock
      System and a hand-weapons locker. The main wall
      is occupied by the scanner screen, astrogation console and
      main systems monitors.</p>
      <p>[bp]The drive sector[/pb] houses the directional thrusts, the
      System Space Kruger &apos;lightfast&apos; motors, and the Irrikon
      Thru-Space drives. Also here are the rear laser housings,
      the ECM capsule, the Zieman shield generators, and
      energy banks, and the Witch-Space fuel condensors
      (Quirium). There are both internal and external access
      panels. Radiation level is high.</p>
      <p>[bp]The living and hygiene section[/pb] is below the main bridge,
      and reached through a descending gravity well. Two
      bunks, food dispensing facilities, waste disposal (including
      high-tox copper exudate for Aonians), SynPleasure
      relaxapads, and videos.</p>
      <p>[bp]The equipment level[/pb] runs throughout the ship, and
      houses all energy banks for lasers, plus the missile rests,
      with dispatch shafts to the lower hull. The communications
      centre is here, and the escape pod (with a
      separate entrance from the bridge) life support systems,
      cryogen tanks (two) and forty cubic metres of FacsEnvironment
      for emergency use.</p>
    </Text>
  </Content>
  <Next>int_status</Next>
  <Previous>intro</Previous>
</Page>

