<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Introductory Data</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
      <p>Welcome aboard this Cobra Mk III trading and combat
      craft. The ship has been supplied to you by Faulcon
      deLacy Spaceways, by arrangement with the Galactic
      Co-operative of Worlds whose Space and Interstellar
      Pilot&apos;s Exams you have just successfully completed. The
      small flight manual supplied with the craft is designed to
      familiarize you with all aspects of space flight, combat,
      and trading, and we hope that it will be of use to you.</p>
      <p>You begin your career, your ship equipped with a single
      forward-firing pulse laser, three homing missiles, 7 light
      years of fuel, and the sum of 100 Credits (Cr), ready to
      embark from a space station in orbit around the planet
      Lave.</p>
      <p>The Cobra Mk III is the best of the medium-range,
      medium capacity fighter-traders, and is an ideal ship for
      new traders intent on building their fortunes, or new
      combateers who will constantly need to finance the cost
      of both armaments and non-combative equipment.</p>
      <p>The ship is highly manoeuvrable, has a good C-holding
      factor during hyperspace transit, can hold sufficient
      Quirium H-fuel for a 7-light-year single jump and has full
      AutoTrading Systems Link for use at space stations.
      Further, it is protected by dual Zieman Energy Deflection
      Shields, powered by four energy banks, and has a
      powerful, rapid-fire pulse laser mounted on the forward
      hull segment. Flight controls are elegant and simple, and
      the bridge is equipped with both HoloDirect, and
      ThruSpace GravDistort communications systems. Its life
      support functions are varied and flexible to ensure
      maximum comfort during trading or hunting operations.</p>
      <p>Pilot licenses are issued only at the planet Lave, and it is
      likely, therefore, that you are now docked at a Coriolis
      station in orbit around that particular world. Lave is a
      rich, agricultural dictatorship, but is a reasonably safe
      world at which to begin your endeavours. GalCop and
      the Lave Authorities allow practice docking and departure
      runs to all their space stations here, and you would
      be advised to take advantage of this facility.</p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="cobra">
      <Text>
        The Cobra Mk III
        incorporates Zieman
        Deflection Shields, fore
        and aft, 4 hull mountings
        for Ingram &apos;rapid-fire&apos;
        pulse lasers, a Lance &amp;
        Ferman &apos;seek &amp; kill&apos;
        missile system, a
        Holodirect &amp; ThruSpace
        GravDistort
        communications system,
        and provision for a cargo
        bay extension.
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>int_interior</Next>
</Page>

