<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Docking Procedure</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
      <p>Docking with a Coriolis space station is never easy, unless the
      ship is equipped with an automatic docking computer. The Navy Training
      Manual recommends the following approach and dock sequence.</p>
      <p>Locate the Coriolis station and approach it. The entrance tunnels
      to all these stations face the mother planet. Fly near to the station
      and then on towards the planet (monitoring altitude carefully). By
      turning a half circle you will now find your ship orientated towards
      the entrance.</p>
      <p>Approach the final moments of docking at [b]DEAD SLOW SPEED.[/b]
      Failure to dock cleanly can be fatal but may simply result in your
      scraping the sides of the aperture, with consequent loss of defensive
      shield(s) and quite possibly your cargo. Manually control the
      Cobra&apos;s roll motion to match the rotation of the Coriolis station
      (see illustration). The entry port must be as nearly horizontal as
      possible.</p>
      <p>If docking is successful; the protective field across the station
      entrance is penetrated, and a break pattern appears on your front view
      screen. Berthing is handled automatically.</p>
      <p>Docking protocol, and Orbit Space Regulations, are numerous, and
      are available in the [i]GC Orbit and System Space Code,[/i] published
      by [i]Federation Planet Bureau.[/i]</p>
      <p>[b]It is stronly advised that you practise docking before
      hyperspacing to your target world by re-entering Lave station.[/b]</p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="docking_1">
      <Text>
      	Accelerate towards Lave, then slow down, stop and loop over to face
      	the station.
      </Text>
    </Image>
    <Image name="docking_2">
      <Text>
      	Set the station in your sights, and make your approach slow and in
      	the final moments dead slow. When just outside the station egress,
      	&apos;correct&apos; the gyration of your ship by manipulating the
      	left/right controls until the entrance tunnel appears horizontal.
      </Text>
    </Image>
    <Image name="docking_3">
      <Text>
	Provided velocity is low, even if you scrape the sides of the
	tunnel, you will survive, though possibly at the expense of some of
	your defensive shields.
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>interplanet</Next>
  <Previous>nav_intergal</Previous>
</Page>

