<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Making For Your Target World</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
    	<p>Having left the space station you will be in low orbit above the
    	planet Lave, moving at low velocity. Decrease your velocity to
    	absolute minimum before coding the astrogation console for
    	Hyperspace Jump.</p>
    	<p>During space flight, you can access the four different views
    	around your ship by tapping the respective section on the scanner,
    	or by sliding your finger horizontally over the scanner.</p>
	<InlineImage name="in_flight_buttons"/>
	<p>Use the button [pb]1[/bp] to display the on board computer. You can
	use the command console to go to the galactic or local chart and
	pick a planet in order to set it as your hyperspace target. Caution:
	Do not forget that your Cobra continues flying while you interact
	with the computer.</p>
	<p>When you have selected a target in range of your current
	hyperspace fuel, the hyperspace button [pb]2[/bp] will appear. Once
	you tap it, the hyperjump motors will engage after a short delay.
	</p>
	<p>On arrival in a new planetary system, after transit from
	hyperspace, you will find yourself at some distance from your target
	world. This conforms with GC Flight Law.</p>
	<p>Even in the safest systems there can be unseen dangers, and you
	will be well advised to approach orbit space, and the safety of the
	space station, as quickly as possible. Increase forward velocity to
	maximum. At this point, you can take full advantage of the torus
	drive ([pb]3[/bp]). Inter-space jumping does not function (because of
	interference patterns) if there is another ship, a planet, or a star
	in the immediate vicinity.</p>
	<p>Therefore, you can use your Cobra&apos;s internal time
	acceleration feature ([pb]4[/bp]) even when friendly ships are close
	by. It puts you into a mild form of stasis, so time appears to pass
	much faster. In reality, your brain operates more slowly, which is
	why the use of the time accelerator is prohibited in the safe zone
	as it led to many crashes and even the destruction of the Space
	Station around Getius in 3187. The accelerator will be turned off
	automatically, if enemy ships arrive.</p>
	<p>Soon your ship&apos;s computer will pick up the beacon signals of
	the nearest orbital space station and will re-engage the compass to
	track that instead of the target planet. Once the Cobra is within
	scanning and protective range of the Coriolis station, the flight
	grid scanner will begin to track it. Its own defenses are now
	available for your protection. The scan console will register the
	letter [bp]S[/pb] as long as the space station is within range.
	</p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="views">
      <Text>
      	You can tap the different zones of your flight grid scanner to
        change the current view. You can look to your right, behind you, to
        your left, or forward again, by tapping the respective section of
        the scanner, or by sliding your finger horizontally over the scanner
        (depending on your personal settings).
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>nav_intergal</Next>
  <Previous>nav_console</Previous>
</Page>

