<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Navigational Controls</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
      <p>It is important that you do [b]not[/b] select [ip]Launch[/pi] from
      the command console for the moment.</p>
      <p>[pb]Galactic chart.[/bp] This chart shows all registered worlds
      within the galaxy, and indicates your own coordinate position. The
      cursor may be used to scan the shown worlds for potentially favourable
      trade sites.</p>
      <p>To view the galactic chart, select [ip]Galaxy[/pi] from the
      command console.</p>
      <p>Touch a star system with your finger in order to select it, the
      cursor will then move to the selected system. In order to zoom out or
      in, use two fingers, put them on the chart and move them apart or
      together.</p>
      <p>[pb]Worldata link.[/bp] After you selected a star system on the
      galactic chart, you may select [ip]Planet[/pi] from the command
      console in order to bring up information on the selected system.</p>
      <p>The Orbit Space Authority takes no responsibility for the accuracy
      of the information registered here, but the trader may gain some idea
      of the relative wisdom of trading with the world whose data is
      displayed. The information shown is distance, type of main life form,
      degree of agricultural or industrial development, with industrial and
      technological level displayed on a scale of 1-15. The government type,
      ranging from Corporate State to Anarchy, will be a strong indication
      of the danger of trading with the system.</p>
      <p>Use [ip]Galaxy[/pi] to return to the chart and acquire
      information about some more planets.</p>
      <p>The red circle is centered around the current position of your ship
      and indicates how far it can jump with its current hyperspace fuel.
      </p>
      <p>Hit the [ip]Home[/pi] button to reset the cursor to your
      ship&apos;s position.</p>
      <p>[pb]Local navigational chart.[/bp] This is a high power chart of all
      planets in the immediate vicinity of your docking world. Since the
      Cobra ship has a maximum single H-jump range of 7 light years, the
      target world must be chosen carefully. The target cursor, used in
      conjunction with the Worldata link, will indicate dangerous or likely
      worlds for trade.</p>
      <p>Hit [ip]Local[/pi] on the command console in order to bring up
      the local navigational chart.</p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="planet_reorte">
      <Text>
        A planetary status card. Whether you choose to amass kills by bounty
	hunting or take the less dangerous course of the traditional trader
	and defensive combateer, the political and economic infrastructure
	of planets should influence the route you take through a galaxy (see
	Interplanetary Travel and Trade).
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>nav_coriolis</Next>
  <Previous>navigation</Previous>
</Page>

