<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Navigation and Flying</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
      <p>The Galactic Co-operative is only one - although the
      largest - of several planetary federations, and maintains
      trade and diplomatic links with over 2000 planets spread
      throughout 8 galaxies. The political profile of a planet is
      an important navigational consideration as many are in a
      state of anarchy and are unsafe to visit in poorly
      equipped ships. Important too is its economic profile, as
      will be discussed in the section about trading.</p>

      <p>Navigational strategy depends of course upon your aims
      in life. If you think you have what it takes to become élite,
      you will need to chart your path through the galaxies
      with care and great precision. You will wish to equip your
      ship as fully and as early as possible. You will, therefore,
      need to study the trading section of this library so that
      you can work out a profitable trading route in order to be
      able to afford the weaponry you will require. You will
      have to make decisions about how dangerous a life you
      wish to lead; in general, the more risks you take
      (traveling to dangerous planets or trading in contraband
      goods), the faster you may equip your ship but the
      quicker you will be killed. You will discover that life in the
      8 galaxies is a question of fine balance. Although it may
      seem, at first, that indiscriminate carnage is a soft option
      (kills improve your rating, after all), as your skills and
      experience of living in space mature, you will quickly
      discover that piracy is a short-lived career.</p>

      <p>Success in this context is a mosaic of talents: combative,
      certainly, but thinking and decision-making talents, too.</p>

      <p>Here you are introduced to all the controls which will
      eventually be useful to you in developing a route
      through the 8 galaxies.</p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="galchart">
      <Text>
        There are 8 galaxies (of
        which this is one), and
        over 250 recognized
        planets in each galaxy. So
        massive a universe
        contains very little that is
        completely predictable,
        and offers infinite
        opportunities for
        adventure.
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>nav_controls</Next>
  <Previous>int_rating</Previous>
</Page>

