<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Alien Races</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
        <p>Of the 2040 officially registered planets in the GalCop, about
        half support human colonies only, that is to say, human presence
        elsewhere is restricted to settlements in under-populated parts of
        the land surface.</p>
        <p>Trading at such worlds depends, for its success, very much upon
        the extant state of co-operation between human and alien. Humans
        control the Coriolis stations in orbit, but the availability of
        items for trade, and their relative expense, can be affected by
        the controlling life forms.</p>
        <p>Most alien life forms are either too primitive, or too glad of
        off-World trade, to interfere. Some, such as the Reptiloid life
        form of Esanbe or the Amphibioids of Anbeen, can make a
        trader&apos;s life very difficult, by haggling at the point of a
        laser.</p>
        <p>The available planetary information on all worlds will indicate
        the nature of the inhabiting life form.</p>
        <p>[b]Bird-forms.[/b] Dealing in alien artefacts on such worlds
        often involves forming a close liaison with Flight Elders, or Nest
        Elders, and this is very much a job for the specialist. Bird-forms
        are, on the whole, a delight to trade with, and the highest form of
        honour (fairly universally) that an off-worlder can receive is an
        invitation to &apos;keep the eggs warm for a moment&apos;.</p>
        <p>[b]Amphibioids[/b] are usually a lot sharper than their wet,
        sluggish appearance would suggest. They are usually keen to trade in
        narcotics, or exotic foodstuffs. Skin creams are always well
        received. Technologically they tend to be backward, but will pay
        high prices for such middle-range items as automated ponds, croak
        metres, spawn freezers and swamp purifiers.</p>
        <p>[b]Felines[/b] are dangerous in the extreme. No matter what sort
        of political structures the world may have, feline aliens are pack
        orientated, and feudal, and very unpredictable. All traders are
        advised to wear body suits, to prevent secretions of sweat from
        triggering a feeding response among these hostile and enigmatic
        life forms.</p>
        <p>To win the confidence of a feline alien is almost invariably to
        be invited to mate, so a certain aloofness is recommended.</p>
        <p>[b]Insectoids.[/b] The most dangerous insectoidal life form is
        the Thargoid, which is mentioned in the Combat section. Insectoidals
        are usually highly intelligent, often existing as a group mind.
        There is rarely any individuality among insectoids, and the trader
        must beware making deals in such a way. One life form builds earth
        cities up to four miles high, and over four million drones live in
        the middle levels. According to the legend, any trader who
        voluntarily ascends the earth passageway from ground to upper
        surface of these immense mounds is honoured with the rare title
        Ascender of the Scent City. And then consumed alive. But trading
        with insectoids can be immensely profitable, as there are so many
        of them (to trade in wrist watches, for example, means two to four
        watches per individual in a clone-group of perhaps ten
        thousand).</p>
        <p>In dealing with [i]any[/i] alien life-form, for the purposes of
        trade, there are three cardinal rules:</p>
        <table>[m]Learn the body language of the alien race;
        Cover up your body scent;
        Beware of Carapace concealed weapons.;
        </table>
    </Text>
  </Content>
  <Next>shipguide</Next>
  <Previous>pol_t_anar</Previous>
</Page>

