<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Advice to Traders</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
        <p>The Cobra trade ship can be fitted with four lasers, four
        missiles and one energy bomb. This should be sufficient to make
        trade possible within the System Space of even heavily piratised
        worlds. But it is strongly recommended that pilots achieve a combat
        of at least &apos;Deadly&apos; before any worlds designated
        &apos;Anarchy&apos; or &apos;Feudal&apos; are approached, especially
        if the cargo is high tech machinery or luxury goods.</p>
        <p>To make money as a trader is no easy task. Unless you have
        backing capital you would be well advised to start with foodstuffs,
        textiles, minerals and luxuries.</p>
        <p>Demand for goods varies widely and prices within planets
        fluctuate, but GalCop regulations prohibit planets from advertising
        their requirements or announcing their market prices beyond their
        own System Space. Any trader, therefore, approaces all transactions
        with a certain financial risk.</p>
        <p>Trade depends upon demand, and selling prices depend upon the
        [i]level[/i] of demand on the planet, and its available money. None
        of these factors can be assessed before entering the system.</p>
        <p>Agricultural planets invariably have excess produce at reasonable
        purchase prices, and such food sells well at industrialised, middle-
        to high-technology worlds. Raw materials, and ores, will sell well
        to middle-tech worlds, which are usually able to refine them, and
        the refined product can fetch excellent prices at worlds of very
        high tech status.</p>
        <p>The rules are complex, and anarchy and piracy has its effect on
        causing the rules to change.</p>
        <p>In trading with a planet, consider its economic profile:</p>
        <p>[b]Agricultural worlds[/b] need specialist food and raw
        materials, but mostly basic machinery and spare parts. If they are
        rich, they need luxuries and high tech industrial machines. They
        produce food in quantity, raw materials and specialised
        &apos;organic&apos; items, like some textiles</p>
        <p>[b]Industrial worlds[/b] need agricultural produce; raw materials
        (for refining); resource exploitation machinery; (if rich) high tech
        goods. They produce basic items of [i]need[/i] for civilised worlds:
        beds, seals and gaskets, power storage units, basic weapons, mass
        produced fertiliser, mass produced medicines etc.</p>
        <p>Think about a planet&apos;s [i]needs[/i].</p>
        <p>Think what might make the [i]society[/i] function.</p>
        <p>Don&apos;t trade expensive trivia to a hungry world.</p>
        <p>[b]IF THE PROFIT ISN&apos;T WORTH IT, TRADE IT SOMEWHERE ELSE.[/b]</p>
    </Text>
  </Content>
  <Next>trade_alt</Next>
  <Previous>trade_how</Previous>
</Page>

