<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Your Rating as a Combateer</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
      <p>To become an élite combateer requires great skill and
      great patience, because expert trading is essential before
      the necessary more powerful armaments and equipment
      available to the Cobra ship can be bought: beam
      lasers, more missiles, energy bombs, a docking computer,
      galactic hyperdrive, etc.</p>
      <p>As you sail through space between the stars, and as you
      trade, you will [i]live[/i] with your combat rating. You will
      begin as [b]HARMLESS[/b]. If you survive your first skirmish
      you may be reclassified as [b]MOSTLY HARMLESS[/b]. But on
      the slow climb to a status level that reflects a growing
      talent for combat you will have to engage many different
      ships, in many different skirmishes, in the System Space
      of many different worlds. You will be classified as [b]POOR[/b],
      then [b]AVERAGE[/b], then [b]ABOVE AVERAGE[/b], then [b]COMPETENT[/b].
      Then you will become [b]DANGEROUS[/b], then
      [b]DEADLY[/b]. And at last, a few will become [b]ELITE[/b].</p>
      <p>Your kills are photographed and transmitted by TS
      ComDirect to the nearest GalCop Federal Law Centre.
      Your rating as a combateer will increase in direct
      proportion.</p>
      <p>Fly your Cobra craft wisely and carefully. Remember:
      other pilots may be attempting to increase their own
      combat rating by attacking either innocent traders, or
      police Vipers (the ships of the GalCop Police Force). If
      you resort to such tactics (or if you adopt the fast-credit
      routine and trade in illegal goods) then your combat rating
      may rise, but your legal status: [b]CLEAN, OFFENDER,
      FUGITIVE,[/b] will make you Public Enemy Number One
      with the Federation Crime Monitoring Authority and you
      will not be left alone.</p>
    </Text>
  </Content>
  <Next>navigation</Next>
  <Previous>int_status</Previous>
</Page>

