<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Missiles</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
    	<p>Missiles are always available, whatever the nature of your destination
    	world, though no more than four may be carried at any one time. They are
    	extremely effective weapons and are carried by the larger star ships.
    	Your ship's computer will warn you when one is fired at you with a
    	message on-screen and an audible warning. Unless your ship is fitted
    	with ECM (see below) you will have to outmanouevre the missile, which
    	will home in on you relentlessly. If a missile hits you, it can almost
    	completely exhaust a fully charged shield and, if your shields and
    	energy are low, may well be fatal.</p>
    	<p>Before a missile can be fired it must be locked onto a target. When
    	fired, it will home in on that target and destroy it, unless your enemy
    	successfully takes one of the precautions described above. The missile
    	launch mechanism is very reliable and hardly ever jams. Missiles can
    	be locked onto targets in any view (front, right, rear, or left).</p>
    	<InlineImage name="missile"/>
    	<p>The targetting sequence is engaged by hitting the button shown above.
    	The missile status indicator on the astrogation console will then turn
    	yellow. When any possible target enters the cross-hair region the
    	missile will lock onto it, the missile status indicator turning red.
    	A beep will sound to inform you of this.</p>
    	<p>Pushing the missile button again will fire the missile. Pushing and
    	holding it for a couple of seconds will unarm the missile and abort
    	the launch sequence.</p>
    	<p>[b]Missile specification:[/b] Lance &amp; Ferman Homing Missiles
    	(4x4) are now recommended for all small class trade-combat ships, but
    	can be fitted as part of a mixed design weapon rack. LF missiles have
    	2IL-135 guidance systems, and optional manual directional control
    	overrides. Warhead packed with Terminal 9 explosive, and the 4x4 is
    	invulnerable to all known counteraction, except ECM systems. Capable
    	of Megazon Destruct Force 7. Prototype first used in 2987, during
    	Ineran Wars.</p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="missile_shot">
      <Text>
        Readily available and relatively cheap at 30 Credits,
        missiles are extremely effective weapons. In The picture, this
        ship's energy banks are about to be substantially reduced.
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>ip_w_energybombs</Next>
  <Previous>ip_w_lasers</Previous>
</Page>

