<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Lasers</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
    	<p>Pulse lasers are initially housed only in the front of the ship,
    	and so no sights appear across rear or side views until such time as
    	you have sufficient credits (from combat and trading) to afford
    	lasers for these mountings. As we shall see, with sufficient cash
    	you will also be able to upgrade pulse to more powerful beam lasers.</p>
    	<InlineImage name="fire"/>
    	<p>The Cobra astrogation console accomodates a single laser-fire button
    	shown above. Even fully equipped only one laser may be fired at a time.
    	If a laser overheats it will not fire (observe the laser temperature bar).</p>
    	<p>Lasers are the principal armament of all space fighters.</p>
    	<p>Pulse lasers will be offered for sale at planets of Tech level 3 or above
    	(see Trading). Beam lasers will be offered at Tech level 4 or above. If a
    	beam laser replaces a pulse laser, the price of the pulse laser is refunded
    	after the beam one has been fitted.</p>
    	<p>[b]Pulse laser specification:[/b] Ingram Model 1919A4 Pulse Laser is
    	recommended for all positional laser mountings, but is especially effective
    	for rear-shooting. Fires intermittent laser &apos;rods&apos; with a cycle
    	rate of 1500 RoPM. The barrel is of high grade Allutium fibre, lined with
    	tempered QuQuorian Silica. Power provided directly from inverse energy
    	banks contained in main ship's drive. Each rod is capable of piercing
    	267mm of Flux-Locked metal.</p>
    	<p>[b]Beam laser specification:[/b] Ingram Model M1928A2 is
    	[i]highly recommended[/i] for front shooting. Beam lasers fire continuous
    	laser strands, up to 150 in parallel. Barrel is Allutium and lined with
    	tensioned plastiglass, and as with the 1919A4 Pulse laser, power is provided
    	by main drive link. Beam lasers are capable of slicing through 410mm
    	FL metal.</p>
    	<p>Military lasers are the very height of sophistication. Costing fifteen
    	times the price of a pulse laser and available only on planets at Tech
    	level 10, it is an extremely effective piece of hardware.</p>
    	<p>(See alo Mining lasers under [b]Non-combative Equipment[/b] )</p>
    	<p>[b]Military laser specification:[/b] Range and penetration twice
    	as effective as the Ingram model M1928A2 beam laser. This is
    	Lance &amp; Ferman&apos;s entré into the laser market. Hitherto known
    	for their highly effective and relatively cheap missile systems,
    	in the military laser they have in effect created a whole new
    	laser market. The LF90 is the current computer-aided model and
    	comes with x4SUSAT sights.</p>
    </Text>
  </Content>
  <Next>ip_w_missiles</Next>
  <Previous>ip_weaponry</Previous>
</Page>

