<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Basic Manoeuvres</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
	<p>The Cobra trade ship needs practice to fly well, though it is
	highly manoeuvrable, very fast, and a good combat vessel. It
	accelerates and decelerates rapidly using fingertip control, which
	can be configured to your preferences in the settings.</p>
	<p>[pb]Anticlockwise roll[/bp] rotate your control device
	anticlockwise, or touch the left part of the control pad, or touch
	the left arrow on the HUD.</p>
	<p>[pb]Clockwise roll[/bp] rotate your control device clockwise, or
	touch the right part of the control pad, or touch the right arrow
	on the HUD.</p>
	<p>[pb]Dive[/bp] tilt your control device away from you, or touch the
	upper part of the control pad, or touch the up arrow on the HUD.</p>
        <p>[pb]Climb[/bp] tilt your control device towards you, or touch the
        lower part of the control pad, or touch the down arrow on the HUD.
        </p>
        <p>[pb]Increase speed[/bp] slide your finger from bottom to top in
        the upper half of your view screen.</p>
        <p>[pb]Decrease speed[/bp] slide your finger from top to bottom in
        the upper half of your view screen.</p>
        <p>Notice the small dot moving around inside the large circle on
        the dials. This is your compass; the dot corresponds to the position
        of the space station. If the dot is green then the station is behind
        you. When the dot is red and in the center of the circle, you should
        be able to see the space station directly in front of you.</p>
        <p>Practice rotating the space station off the screen and using the
        compass to find it again.</p>
        <p>You might see some Cobra Class ships. These are other traders
        like yourself, and will not harm you unless you shoot at them. If
        you do this they will either attack or, alternatively, run away.
        Should you use them for combat practice, do not expect the space
        station to turn a blind eye to such unruly behaviour. Nothing will
        attack you while you are within sight of the space station - unless
        you make a nuisance of yourself.</p>
        <p>It is not possible to land on the planet, and flying into planets
        or space stations is fatal. The altimeter shows your height above
        the planet&apos;s surface, and you should not let it fall too low.</p>
        <p>(If you are a new pilot, now is your best chance to practice
        docking manoeuvres with the space station at Lave. The Lave Orbit
        Space Authority permits an unlimited number of practice runs by
        newly appointed pilots, and does not charge. This facility is
        suspended during attack, or when the Coriolis station has no free
        docking space. See the illustrated section on docking procedure.)
        </p>
    </Text>
    <Image name="rearview_coriolis">
      <Text>
	Looking back at the Coriolis station where your Cobra was berthed.
      </Text>
    </Image>
  </Content>
  <Next>nav_console</Next>
  <Previous>nav_leaving</Previous>
</Page>

