<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Page>
  <Header>Intergalactic Trading</Header>
  <Content>
    <Text>
        <p>The Cobra Mk. III, designed primarily as a trading ship, combines
        combat efficiency and manoeuvrability with substantial cargo space
        (20 Tonne Canisters) and with scoop attachments for space debris,
        jettisoned cargo and space rock.</p>
        <p>Most space stations have made the process of trading very simple,
        in order to facilitate a fast turnover in goods and ships. Import
        and export tariffs -- which are high on some worlds -- are
        automatically added or deducted and this is reflected in the prices
        shown. The auto-trader system, employed by the Cobra, does not allow
        for more specific trading deals to be performed.</p>
    	<p>A selection of the more valuable alien items that are tradeable
    	is given in this manual, but the trader must deal with them in
    	person.</p>
    	<p>Once docked you are linked directly with the CorCom Trade System.
    	At your request you can obtain a list of basic trade items available
    	for purchase.</p>
    	<p>Slaves are measured by the tonne in galactic trading. This may
    	seem a little strange, but it includes the cryogenic suspension
    	system necessary to keep them alive during space travel. The slave
    	trade, once almost eliminated by the Galactic Government is now
    	returning, despite the efforts of the Galactic Police Force to
    	suppress it.</p>

    	<table>,[pb]Item[/bp],[pb]Description[/bp],[r][pb]Average Price/Cr[/bp],[pb]Unit[/bp];
    	       ,Food,Simple organic products[c] see below,4.8,tonne;
    	       ,Textiles,Unprocessed fabrics,7.1,tonne;
    	       ,Radioactives,Ores and by-products,22.8,tonne;
	       *,Slaves,Usually humanoid,14.7,tonne;
    	       ,Liquor/Wines,Exotic spirits from unearthly flora,28.6,tonne;
    	       ,Luxuries,Perfumes[c] Spices[c] Coffee,91.3,tonne;
    	       *,Narcotics,Tobacco[c] Arcturan Megaweed,161.1,tonne;
    	       ,Computers,Intelligent machinery,83.1,tonne;
    	       ,Machinery,Factory and farm equipment,56.9,tonne;
    	       ,Alloys,Industrial Metals,38.7,tonne;
    	       *,Firearms,Small-scale artillery[c] sidearms etc.,83.0,tonne;
    	       ,Furs,Includes leathers[c] Millennium Wompom Pelts,69.4,tonne;
    	       ,Minerals,Unrefined rock containing trace elements,8.7,kg;
    	       ,Gold,,38.5,kg;
    	       ,Platinum,,71.4,kg;
    	       ,Gem-stones,Includes jewellery,19.4,g;
    	       ,Alien Items,Artefacts[c] Weapons etc.,44.7,tonne;
    	       ,Medical Supplies,Pills[c] ointments[c] syringes etc.,96.5,tonne;</table>
    	<p>* These items are defined as illegal by the Galactic Government,
    	so trading them is risky.</p>
    </Text>
  </Content>
  <Next>trade_how</Next>
  <Previous>ip_n_retrorockets</Previous>
</Page>

